Kevin McGrath

I am a Full-Stack Software developer with a background in Fine Arts; Design; Mathematics; Art and Technology.

Github | LinkedIn | My Personal Site

Cell: 708-341-8763 Email: kpmcgra@gmail.com

Location: Chicago, Il.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Java, MAX/MSP, and Javascript | Frameworks/Libraries: Flask, Django,
Spring, Maven, and Bootstrap | Databases: MySql, SQL | Tools: Git, VS Code, Spring Tools,
Amazon Web Services | HTML, CSS, SASS.

Two full-stack development certifications from Coding Dojo in Java and Python using Spring, Maven, and Flask frameworks. Trained in MYSQL and relational databases. Spring Tool Suite for Java development.

I have a Master of Fine Arts in Sound from the School of the Art institute of Chicago. I work extensively with digital sound synthesis in the MAX/MSP programming language.

I have also studied pure mathematics and formal logic independently for over 10 years and have been a part of two independent research groups led by mathematics Phd's Lou Kauffman and Eugenia Cheng. I was recently a part of a group that helped Eugenia Cheng get feedback on her recently published book on category theory: "The Joy of Abstraction."

<u>Technical Projects</u>

- <u>Zineverse</u> a site for independent publishers to host and share their work. Utilizes file management and file uploads for users to share images and pages, with full CRUD capability while also allowing users to connect and share with others.
- Github Link

 Python
 Flask
 Javascript
 MySql
 HTML
 CSS
 Sass

 Bootstrap
 Nginx
 Gunicorn
 NPM
 AWS Ec2
 Restful API

- <u>FashApp:</u> a group project at Coding Dojo for users to curate clothing into collections and outfits. Full CRUD capability, verifications, and file uploads.
- Collaborative project utilizing GitHub for version control and collaboration.
- AWS Ec2 deployment

 Python
 Flask
 MySQL
 HTML
 CSS
 Sass

 Nginx
 Gunicorn
 Npm
 Aws Ec2
 Github
 Bootstrap

 <u>Personal Site:</u> This is my personal networking site. It is built entirely on HTML, Javascript, CSS and bootstrap. Utilizes SMTP JS to handle emails.

Javascript	HTML	css	Github.io	Sass	Bootstrap
------------	------	-----	-----------	------	-----------

Professional Experience

Head Preparator | Carrie Secrist Gallery

2022-Current

- Managed all transportation, construction, packing, staffing and storage for art exhibitions, art installations, and all art related services at Carrie Secrist Gallery.
- Allocated an annual budget of 25,000.00.

Project Manager | Midwest Tropical Custom Water Features

2021-2022

- Designed fully custom water features with CAD software.
- On-site manager for rigging installations.
- Project management: managed purchasing tools and equipment, fabrication, and shipping for over 30 projects.
- promotional graphic design with photoshop and illustrator.

Project Manager and Woodshop Manager | Cadogan Tate Fine Art 2021-2022

- Built and managed the woodshop for crates and general construction. Trained personnel in art handling, safety, and building methods.
- Managed projects, conducted site visits and consultations. Handled all inventory and purchasing for the woodshop.

Education

<pre>Coding Dojo Full-Stack Developer Certificate</pre>	2022-2023
School of The Art Institute of Chicago Master of Fine Arts	2017-2019
Illinois State University Bachelors of Science in Fine Arts	2006-2010